[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Mike.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Mike
Hello everyone.
大家好
Design is hard but design
设计是困难的 但是
presentations are way harder.
关于设计的演讲是更困难的
I still find them daunting.
我一直觉得它们使人感到畏惧
And today, a presentation about
今天 我将在 WWDC
how to present design work at
演讲一个关于 如何
WWDC.
展示设计作品的话题
The struggle is real.
这真的很挣扎
In any presentation, we have to
在任何演讲中
take this big and complex topic
我们都必须承担这个大而复杂的话题
and explain it precisely.
并且精确地解释它
Take it right down to its
准确的解释
nucleus.
它的核心
And if we don't do that well,
如果我们做的不好
those ideas might die.
这些想法可能会凋谢
All that hard work you did
你所做的所有艰苦工作
resigned to the depths of your
你硬盘中的存储深度
hard drive.
都将消失
Presentation matters.
演讲很重要
As a designer at Apple, I have
作为 Apple 公司的设计师
to present design work all the
我必须时刻展示
time.
设计的作品
Unfortunately, this year I can't
不幸的事 今年我无法
show you too much of that, but
向你展示太多的内容
I'm going to try and transmit to
但我会尝试向你们传达它
you the ten most important
我在接下来的 9 分钟
things I've learned about
介绍我在设计工作时
presenting design work in the
所学到的
next nine minutes or so.
十个最重要的事情
It's going to be punchy.
这将非常的简洁并且有力
Now when you really think about
现在 当你真正思考它时
it, there are three fundamental
在这演讲中 有着三个
parts to a presentation.
基本的部分
There is me, the presenter, the
有我 主持人
emotional designer consumed by
被这个问题所充满的
this problem and the prettiness
情感设计师 以及它
of it.
的可爱之处
And there is you, the audience,
还有你 观众
detectives of design crime,
设计犯罪的侦探
guardians of good sense,
理智的保卫者
Draculas of deadlines, and
最后期限的德古拉斯
captains of code.
以及代码队长
And between us, there is this
在我们中间 有着
central idea.
一个核心想法
The thing we need to agree is
我们共同赞同的事情需要
good for our company, good for
对我们公司有好处
our customers, something that
对我们客户有好处
makes the world a slightly
并且可以使世界变得
better place.
更加美好
Let's call it a toaster.
让我们称之为烤面包机
And really a presentation is
实际上 演讲是一种
just a mechanism to exchange
交流关于该想法
information about that idea, to
的信息的机制 以便
facilitate decisions and action
以某种方式促进
one way or another, to make this
决策和行动 从而使这想法
thing fly or crash right back
可以飞翔或者直接坠毁
down to Earth.
到地底
So dear presenter, these are the
所以亲爱的主持人
key things you need to
这些是你需要理解的关键
What are your objectives for
你这次演讲的
this presentation?
目标是什么
Clarify your objectives.
澄清你的目标
Are you trying to get this work
你是试图让你的上司
approved by your superiors or
批准这项工作
successfully communicate with
或者使之能与工程师
engineers?
成功的交流
Maybe you're pitching a new
也许你正在创造一个新的想法
Try to imagine what succeeding
尝试想象成功的
looks like and work backwards
样子 并且从那里
from there.
往回走
Identify the questions you need
确定你需要你的观众
your audience to help you
来帮助你回答的问题
State these and your goals up
提前说明这些
front.
和你的目标
And understand the objectives of
并了解你的观众的目标
What do they care about?
他们关心什么
Remember, your objectives
记住 你的目标
include addressing theirs.
包括处理他们的目标
Try not to dive in to details
在阐述更大的图像之前
and minutia before you clarify
尽量不要去详细
the bigger picture.
描述细节
Next is a big one: feedback.
接下来非常的重要 反馈
As designers, we feel vulnerable
作为一个设计师 我们感到
and exposed, painting our finest
脆弱和暴露 画出我们
pictures and teeing them up to
最好的图片 并把它们撕成碎片
Try to entertain the mindset
试着让自己觉得没有失败
feedback.
只有反馈
Take all of it seriously even
即使你不同意
when you disagree.
也要认真对待
If you are presenting, you are
如果你正在展示
asking for feedback.
你就需要反馈
It's the whole point and clarify
这就是整个观点
the problems the audience
并解释清观众认同的观点
Sometimes people offer solutions
有时人们提供的
that are unworkable, but the
解决方案不可行 但是
problem they are addressing is
他们发表的问题是
totally valid.
完全有效的
So when you have exhausted all
所以当你觉得用尽所有的可能性
possibilities, remember this,
的时候 记住这一点
you really haven't.
你真的还没有达到那一步
People in your audience will
听众中的人会知道
know things you don't.
你不知道的信息
So be willing to change your
所以你需要愿意改变你的立场
position, especially when new
特别是在当
information has been presented.
新信息被提出的时候
Don't pretend to understand
不要假装理解
unclear feedback.
不清楚的反馈信息
Clarify the problem this person
弄清楚这个人所要
is trying to address.
表达的问题
Don't respond like that.
不要像这样进行回复
And don't be dismissive or get
也不要轻言放弃
overly defensive.
或者轻言放肆
It really won't help your case.
这真的对你的情况有任何帮助
Seek advice.
寻求建议
Use the wisdom of your
使用你的同事的智慧
Don't be afraid to ask for help.
不要害怕寻求帮助
They know how this works.
他们知道这是如何工作的
Their input is priceless.
他们的投入是无价的
Practice with them.
与他们进行实践
Sense check your deck.
仔细检查你的想法
Do a full practice run if it
如果它值得的话 做一个
merits it.
完整的实践运行
Do not deliver it blind.
不要盲目的交付
The feedback will make a huge
反馈会造成巨大的不同
And honestly, don't try to do
坦白地说 不要试图自己做
everything yourself.
所有的事情
Teamwork makes the dream work
团队合作产生理想工作
plus it's really hard to keep
并且一个人跟踪太多的
track of too many disparate
不同的事情是非常
things as one person, let alone
困难的 让他们单独做自己的部分
try and explain them to others
然后在一个简单的演讲中
in a single presentation.
介绍自己的部分给别人听
Use your own voice.
用你自己的声音
Be genuine.
真诚 有趣
Make terrible jokes.
讲糟糕的笑话
Quote Bruce Lee.
引用 Bruce Lee
You wouldn't be giving this
如果你没有可信度
presentation at all if you
你就根本不会
didn't have the credibility.
做这个演讲
You've earned it.
你已经赢得了它
Express your opinion.
表达了你的意见
You are the expert here.
你是这里的专家
The audience wants to know what
观众想知道你的想法
you think and that doesn't mean
但这并不意味着
you have to have all the
你需要知道所有的答案
Show your passion.
展现你的激情
Why do you care about this?
为什么你在乎这些
And explain your process.
并解释你的过程
Show the journey you've been on.
展示你一直以来的经历
How and why did you reach these
你为什么得出这些结论
Don't be overconfident or
不要过分自信
insincere.
或者不诚恳
Sometimes designers can adopt a
有时候设计师会采取一种
posture of being super
超自信的姿态
confident, bordering on arrogant
接近傲慢
and avoid that.
要避免这种情况
It's just not cool.
这不是很酷
And don't say what you think
不要说你认为
people want to hear.
人们想听到的东西
Your vote counts for a lot.
你的决定是很重要
The audience.
观众
It's not a presentation without
这不是一个没有
an audience.
观众的演讲
Make sure you show them that
确保你向他们展示
respect.
了这种尊重
You need their cooperation to
你需要他们的合作来给你的
give life to your ideas.
想法注入生命
And if you've presented to this
如果你之前已经向这个观众
audience before, you'll get --
展示过 你将会开始
start to get an idea of what
了解他们的反应
Tailor to them as much as you
尽可能地为他们量身定制
can and always have an agenda.
并且总是遵循一个议程
Here's what we're going to talk
以下是我们要按
about in this order.
顺序讨论的内容
This is also your chance to
这也是你
assert the point at which you'd
提供反馈意见的机会
It almost certainly won't work
它几乎肯定不会像这样的发展
that way but still do try.
但仍然要尝试
And if you've met previously,
如果你以前见过这些
recap what happened.
回顾一下发生了什么
Like when you're engrossed in a
就像当你全神贯注
series but then life happens and
在一系列的事情中 然后事情突然发生
when you pick it up again, you
当你再次捡起它时
really grateful for that 30
你真的很感激那 30 秒
second refresher.
的回顾
Hey, Zach.
嘿 Zach
Here's a study of the character
这是对你要求的角色进行的
that you asked for.
研究的学习
Good feedback.
良好的反馈
I'm not sure about those emoji
我也不确定那些
either.
表情符号是否合适
Integrate their feedback.
整合他们的反馈
Let them know how it affected
让他们知道它是如何影响
your designs.
你的设计的
Show that you're listening and
表明你在倾诉
responding.
和回复
Terrible.
太可怕
Make no assumptions, you know --
不要假设 你知道
people know what things mean or
人们知道这什么意思
why decisions were made.
或者为什么做这个决定
You are much further along this
沿着这条道路你比
path than your audience.
你的观众走的更远
Anticipate their questions.
预测他们的问题
Pay attention to their
注意他们的反应
And be willing to explain.
并愿意解释
Do not show up without a plan or
不要没有计划地去
try to wing it.
尝试展示它们
It's not a good look.
这不会好看的
And also showing your working
并且还会显得你的
files, not good.
工作完成地不好
These things are lazy and
这些事情是懒惰的
disrespectful of people's time.
并且不尊重人们的时间的
And, of course, don't be
当然 不要
dismissive of -- again, don't be
轻视 再次强调
dismissive of anyone's input.
不要轻视任何人的意见
Try to be patient and objective.
尽量保持耐心和客观
Make it relatable to your
让它和你的观众
audience.
产生关联
If not, they may well start to
如果不是 他们可能会开始退出
Let people see themselves in
让人们在你的故事中
your story.
看到他们自己
If you can elicit an emotional
如果你能引起他们的情绪
response, excitement, worry, or
反应 兴奋 担心
even fear, it will enhance their
甚至恐惧 这会
sense of commitment.
加强他们的参与感
Ellis goes crazy for that
Ellis 为接骨木果果酱疯狂
Use what you know about your
用你对你的观众的了解
audience to your advantage.
作为你的优势
Describe what you see and feel.
描述你的看法和感受
Don't talk about users like they
不要说用户是像
are a distant third party.
遥远的第三方
Flow diagrams can be really
流程图对于工程师
useful with engineers but when
来说非常的有用 但在
communicating concepts, there's
沟通概念时
a big disconnect.
会有很大的脱节
Instead, speak in the first
相反我们需要当面的交流
Here I am at my desk working on
这里 我在我的桌面处理工作
my e-mail and ding, a handy
我的邮件 叮铃一声 提醒我
reminder it's time for
现在是时间吃早饭了
I hit the notification and bam,
我点击了一下通知
straightaway I can load my toast
直接地 我可以开始烤我的面包
without even stepping away from
甚至不需要离开
my desk.
我的桌面
Just one swipe down and we're
只需要轻轻一扫 我们就可以烤面包了
And a few minutes later I know
几分钟后 我知道
to be on my way, perfect timing.
它快好了 完美的时间
And how cool is that?
这有多酷啊
I can even see my stats.
我甚至可以看到我的数据
Clearly, this is more powerful
显然 如果你能演示一个原型
if you can demo a prototype.
这将更强而有力
And engage in dialogue.
在对话中进行展示
A presentation should be a
演讲是一个对话
Engage with your audience.
与你的观众进行互动
Design for the aha moment.
设计这个哈哈时刻
If you can lead people through
如果你能引导人们
your story, their minds will try
走进你的故事 他们的头脑会
and predict the ending.
试着预测结局
This will keep them engaged.
这将会使他们与你保持互动
Ask them questions.
向他们提问
Keep them dialed in.
保持他们的参与度
You're here for their feedback
毕竟 你在这里是为了
after all.
他们的反馈
Do not deliver a monologue.
不要提供独白
This is boring and naive.
这是无聊而弱智的
Think of it as a discussion more
把它看作是讨论而不是
than a speech.
一个演讲
And finally, the idea.
最后 想法
It is crucial to explain why.
解释它的原因是至关重要的
Define each problem in a single
用一个句子来定义
sentence.
每个问题
It's a great exercise to really
了解问题的核心
get to the heart of the matter.
是一个非常好的练习
You'll need to find agreement on
你需要和观众
those problem statements with
就这些问题
your audience.
达成一致
Otherwise, you'll be barking up
否则 你将走向错误的道路
Continue to revisit, refine, and
随着你的进步 继续重温
refer back to those statements
提炼并回顾这些陈述
as you progress and, of course,
当然
where you can, show evidence
你还可以证明
that these problems exist.
存在的这些问题
Boom.
糟糕
Cold, burnt toast.
冷的 烤焦的面包
Tragic problems in this world.
这个世界上的悲剧性问题
Avoid using subjective reasoning
都应避免使用主观推理来
for your decisions.
作出决定
I chose this color because I
我选择这种颜色是因为
like it is not remotely
我喜欢它 并不是它很有
persuasive, especially if your
说服力 特别是如果
audience don't share your
你的观众不赞同你的偏好
And the truth is that people
事实上 人们真的
really won't remember your
不会记得你的幻灯片
They'll remember how your story
他们会记住你的故事
made them feel if it resonated
如何让他们感受到它
with them so sketch out the
并使他们共鸣 所以尽早
narrative of your presentation
准备你的
early.
演讲稿
The most successful designers I
我认识的最成功的设计师
know do this.
就是这么做的
It's another thing that will
这是另一回事
help you focus and use your time
它可以帮助你有效的集中
effectively.
和利用你的时间
So where you can, incorporate a
所以你可以 你可以通过
story with a distinct beginning,
明确的开头 中间
middle, and an end.
结尾三个部分来组合一个故事
People intuitively get stories.
人们直观地获得故事
And it'll really help them
这真的会帮助他们继续前进
Contrast today's reality with a
对比今天的实现
better future.
和更美好的未来
Nancy Duarte, a master of
Nancy Duarte 一个演讲大师
presentations, discovered in her
在她的研究中发现
research that some of the
一些最好和
greatest and most effective
最有效的
presentations follow this
演讲稿有着这些结构
structure.
而关键在于
providing the contrast between
在今天的现实
what is today's reality and what
与可能之间提供对比
could be, what the future could
如果我们将想法呈现给
look like if we make the ideas
我们新的现实
we're presenting our new
未来将会是怎么样的呢
Today, people are frustrated,
今天 人们是沮丧
cold, joyless toast.
冷淡 不快乐的烤面包
It's an epidemic.
这是一种流行病
But imagine happy, flawless
但是想象一下你的 iPhone
toast at the top of the button
上按钮上方无暇的
on your iPhone.
开心的吐司
But don't get too carried away.
但不要太离谱
That is a rookie mistake.
这是一个菜鸟的错误
Keep it simple.
把事情简单化
The main thing is to keep the
主要的是保持
main thing the main thing.
主要的东西
I love this quote.
我喜欢这句话
And I always find myself coming
我发现我总是会走回到这一点
It's such a perfect expression.
这是一个完美的表达
If I had more time, I would have
如果我有更多的时间 我会
written a shorter letter.
写一封更短的信
Relevant not only for
不仅适用于
presentations and writing
演示和撰写
e-mails but as a philosophy
电子邮件 而且适用于
toward design.
设计理念
Don't overload people with too
不要灌输人们
much information.
太多的信息
Strip away everything that isn't
剥去一切对你的
essential to your mission or
使命或信息不重要的东西
And finally, don't forget to
最后 不要忘记总结
Know your objectives, otherwise
了解你的目标 否则
what's the point?
有什么意义呢
Embrace feedback.
拥抱反馈
It's what you're here for.
这就是你在这里的原因
Seek advice.
寻求建议
Your colleagues are smart.
你的同事很聪明
And use your own voice.
并善用你的声音
It's the best one you have.
这是你拥有的最好的一个工具
Respect your audience or they
尊重你的观众
won't respect you.
否则他们不会尊重你
Make it relatable, otherwise
与观众产生关联
they'll forget it.
否则观众会忘记你的演讲
Engage in dialogue to keep them
让他们参与对话来
present and explain why.
使他们沉浸其中并解释原因
It's the million dollar
这是一个价值百万美元的问题
Utilize storytelling because it
利用讲故事的技巧 因为
works.
它很有用
And keep it simple even though
使演讲保持简洁明了
it's not.
即使它不是
Good luck with your
祝你演讲顺利
presentations.
好运
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]